ERIC GUSTAFSON

Full Stack Web Developer

720.346.5341

weuxfya@gmail.com

Highlands Ranch, CO



Full stack web developer with a background in systems engineering. I bring my experiences as part of Infrastructure-as-a-Service teams to my work as a developer. Working as part of lean global teams has taught me to be a self-starter focused on shared business goals. Experience with compute, storage, and virtualization. Master of Science in Computer Information Technology with an emphasis in Software Engineering from Regis University - Denver. Certificate from the University of Denver

in full stack web development including HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4, MongoDB, Express, React, and NodeJS. Certified in ITIL, LeanIT, Microsoft MCSE: Cloud, and TOGAF9.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr Staff Systems Engineer
VISA | April 2012 - Present

Independent contributor collaborating across teams to meet shared organizational goals. Create PowerShell scripts for implementing production changes and ad hoc reporting on a 450 node hypervisor infrastructure spread across data centers in the US, UK, and Asia. Manage tasks with Jira and source code in BitBucket. Author wiki to document environment configuration and troubleshooting for Operations teams. Contribute code to automation efforts related to organization's private cloud portal. Work closely with vendors on innovating existing infrastructure. Background and technical skills provide a solid platform for both development and devops roles.

Sr Systems Engineer

Teletech Holdings | December 2010 - April 2012

Developed storage solutions with Storage Engineering to meet specific virtualization workloads. Standardized Vmware hypervisor builds to reduce issues by 85%. Architected and implemented Vmware View 4.6 virtual desktop environment using Cisco UCS and NetApp storage to support 2500 concurrent virtual desktops. Responsible for a large globally disperse VMware vSphere 4.1 environment consisting of more than 115 hosts across the US, UK and Australia and over 60TB of shared storage. Reduced time to implement Vmware configurations by leveraging PowerShell PowerCLI.

Microsoft Systems Engineer II

Catholic Health Initiatives | July 2006 - December 2010

Implemented and supported VMware vSphere 4, Virtual Infrastructure 3.x/ESXi in a 120 VMware ESX Host environment. Consolidated server footprint through implementation of Vmware server virtualization. Reduced the number of physical servers and their impact on Data Center space and cooling. Realized measurable savings for the business. Developed and updated detailed technical documentation to support various projects.

SKILLS

Technical

JavaScript/jQuery

React

Node.js

Express

Agile

Professional

Effective Communication

Focused on Business Goals

Team Player

Good Time Management

Strong Problem Solver

Education

MS Computer Information Systems, Regis University, Denver CO

Full Stack Development Intensive, University of Denver, Denver CO

BA Geology, University of Montana, Missoula MT

Certification

The Open Group Architecture Framework (TOGAF)9

ITIL Foundation

ITIL Intermediate Certificate in IT Service Operation

Lean IT Foundation

Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure (MCSE: Cloud)

https://github.com/eric-gustafson1

https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-gustafson-4006b4/